forth.gr 2018-11-24

# Personal Data Protection Policy

Personal Data Protection Policy
The Foundation for Research and Technology - Hellas (FORTH) pays special attention to the protection of
the visitors’ and users’ privacy and personal data. Please note that personal data means, under the
relevant legislation (General Data Protection Regulation, 2016/679/EU) only information that relates to
an identified or – based on certain characteristics – identifiable natural person (data subject).
Information relating to legal persons and groups of persons or statistical information which do not
enable reduction to an identified or identifiable natural person do not fall within this category and are
exempted from the scope of the relevant legislation.
 This personal data protection policy is fully consistent with the European Union Regulation on the
protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data (EU/2016/679) and Greek
law and is aimed to provide information about the information collected during your visit at the website
of FORTH.
FORTH may modify this policy at any time, without previous notice, by announcing any such
modification on its website. By navigating in and using the FORTH website, visitors/users acknowledge
that they have read, understood and unconditionally accepted the Personal Data Protection Policy.
Data Controller
The personal data controller for the purpose of the operation of this website is as follows:
FOUNDATION FOR RESEARCH AND TECHNOLOGY - HELLAS (FO.R.T.H.)
(Research Organisation private law legal body)
100 N. Plastira Str.
Vassilika Vouton
GR 700 13
HERAKLION, CRETE
The following terms provide important information relating to the type, the purpose of use of your
personal data, their protection, as well as your rights as subjects of these data.
For any further explanation, you may contact the Data Protection Officer (DPO) of FORTH by sending an
e-mail at dpo@admin.forth.gr.
Personal Data Collected by the FORTH Website
During your visit to our website, you are not obliged to provide personal information. We only ask you
to provide personal details when you want to contact us, by filling out the online contact form available
on our website. In that case, we ask you to provide the following details:
- Full name
- Capacity
- Company or organisation
- E-mail address
- Postal address
- Telephone number
of which it is only mandatory to fill out your full name, company/organisation and e-mail.
During your visit at our website, certain information may be automatically collected, such as the IP
address of your computer.

For more information, please check the relevant cookies policy of FORTH below or the Terms of Use.
Our organisation has pages on social media, such as on Facebook, TWITTER, LINKEDIN, and YOUTUBE,
but no data processing is carried out on such web pages. You can contact the administrator of the
relevant web page of FORTH by sending a message. If the administrator of the relevant page receives
messages that contain personal data of natural persons, these shall be strictly confidential and their use
shall exclusively serve the purpose of your communication with the Foundation and, when such purpose
has been met, they shall be deleted.
FORTH does not exercise and cannot exercise influence and control over the nature and extent of the
personal data collected and kept by the social media as a condition or result of their use and may not be
held liable for any collection and processing of personal data by them. For more information about the
purpose of collection and the further processing and use of personal data by social media platforms, as
well as about the rights and available arrangements for protecting your privacy and personal data,
please check the personal data protection policy of the relevant social media.
Purpose and Principles of Personal Data Collection
FORTH collects and processes the personal data of visitors/users exclusively and only with a view to
meeting its purposes and functions and, more specifically, for the purpose of its communication with
you. Processing is limited to personal data that are necessary and appropriate for meeting the purpose
and functions of the website. Processing is subject to the requirements of the General Data Protection
Regulation and the relevant Union law, Greek legislation and international conventions and treaties.
Use of the Personal Data Collected by Us
The personal data we collect from the contact platform available on our website, as well as any other
data that may be sent to us through our profiles on the various social networks, shall be used only for
the needs of our communication with you and for your better service. While navigating on our website,
cookies are used only for the purpose of statistical analysis of the visits to our website. No further
processing, transmission or exchange of these data shall take place. In any event, you are a priori
requested to consent to the above use of your personal data.
Cookies Policy
During users’ navigation on this website, FORTH may collect identification data of users, by using
relevant technologies, such as cookies and/or Internet Protocol (IP) address monitoring. Cookies are
small text segments that are sent to the browser by a website visited by the user. The use of cookies
helps the website to remember information about the user’s visit, such as your preferred language and
your preferences, to make secure searches, to calculate the number of visitors, or to facilitate your
registration in our services.
How to control cookies: You may control and/or delete cookies as you wish. You may find more details
at aboutcookies.org. You may delete all cookies from your computer and, in most browsers, select
settings that do not allow installation of cookies. However, in that case, you may have to adjust certain
preferences every time you visit a website. Users may make use of the website without problems even

without use of cookies, but, potentially, to the detriment of its user-friendliness and of the functioning
of certain of its services.
Any personal data collected via cookies that can be correlated to a specific visitor/user shall be
processed exclusively for the purposes cited above.
For the Newsletter issued by FORTH
A page has been created on FACEBOOK for subscription to the newsletter issued by FORTH
(https://www.facebook.com/ITE.HELLAS/app/100265896690345/). For the purpose of disseminating
and sending the newsletter, users expressing an interest in receiving the newsletter are asked to provide
their full name and email address. The persons concerned may have their name removed from the list of
recipients of the newsletter at any time and the data registered for the above purpose shall be deleted.
Data Transmission/Disclosure to Third Parties
The personal data collected may be disclosed or transmitted to third parties, if this is mandatory for
fulfilling legal obligations or necessary for meeting the purposes and functions of the website, subject to
the safeguards provided for by relevant legislation. We may assign to natural or legal persons the task of
performing certain services and functions of the website. Those persons shall receive only personal data
that are necessary for performing the services assigned and are bound by FORTH to the confidentiality
and safe processing of the personal data.
Your Rights Relating to the Processing of Your Data
In accordance with the provisions of the General Data Protection Regulation (679/2016/EU), you have
the right, both during the collection and afterwards, to be informed about any processing of your
personal data, its purpose, as well as the disclosure/transmission to third parties and their identity (right
of information and access). You have also the right to request that your personal data kept by FORTH be
corrected, updated or deleted. You have also the right to have the processing restricted and the right to
object.
In order to receive information and exercise your rights, you may contact the Personal Data Officer at
dpo@admin.forth.gr.
We point out that, in accordance with the Regulation, you have the right to file a complaint to the Data
Protection Authority.
Confidentiality and Security
The personal data we collect within the context of the operation of the website are those strictly
necessary for the purpose of our communication with you. They are strictly confidential and are kept
only for the needs of such communication. Access to these data is provided to very few officers of the
organisation, who have been bound to keeping confidentiality. Moreover, we have adequate security
systems and take all necessary and appropriate organisational and technical measures in order to
prevent any breach of personal data security (leak, disclosure, unauthorised access) in our systems.

Modification to this Personal Data Protection Policy
This personal data protection policy may change whenever necessary, always in compliance with
national and Union law. For that reason, you are kindly requested to visit this page regularly in order to
be informed. By navigating on and using the FORTH website, visitors/users acknowledge that they have
read, understood and unconditionally accepted the Personal Data Protection Policy.
Contact
If you have any questions relating to this personal data protection policy or if you believe that there is
any vagueness or incompatibility in our personal data protection policy, you may communicate such
instance to the Data Protection Officer (DPO) of FORTH by sending an e-mail at dpo@admin.forth.gr.
